export default Dpe1 = [
    {
        question: "1. Why does water on floor disappear after some time",
        options: ["Due to evaporation of molecules",
            "Due to condensation of molecules",
            "Due to melting of molecules",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Due to evaporation of molecules"
    },

    {
        question: "2. Reverse process of condensation is",
        options: ["Freezing",
            "Melting",
            "Evaporation",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Evaporation"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Rate of evaporation of liquid depends on",
        options: ["Surface area temperature",
            "Amount of vapour already present in the surrounding air",
            "Surface area temperature & Amount of vapour already present in the surrounding air",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Surface area temperature & Amount of vapour already present in the surrounding air"
    },
    {
        question: "4. Condensation is the reverse process of",
        options: ["Humidity",
            "Boiling",
            "Melting",
            "Evaporation"],
        correct_option: "Evaporation"
    },
    {
        question: "5. Specific heat of a substance S=",
        options: ["qm\ΔT ",
            "QM\ΔT",
            "Qm\ΔT",
            "Tm\ΔQ"],
        correct_option: "Qm\ΔT"
    },
    {
        question: "6. The average kinetic energy of the molecules is ____ to the absolute temperature.",
        options: ["Directly proportional",
            "Inversely proportional",
            "Equal",
            "None of these"],
        correct_option: "Directly proportional"
    },
    {
        question: "7. The heat energy required to convert 1 g of solid completely into liquid at a constant temperature is called",
        options: ["Latent heat of water",
            "Latent heat of fusion",
            "Latent heat of vapourization",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Latent heat of fusion"
    },

    {
        question: "8. Which of the following substance has light specific heat ?",
        options: ["Iron",
            "Kerosene oil",
            "Ice",
            "Water"],
        correct_option: "Water"
    },
    {
        question: "9. Rate of evaporation of liquid depends upon",
        options: ["Surface area",
            "Temperature",
            "Water vapour in surrounding air",
            "All"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },

    {
        question: "10. The boiling point of water in Celsius is",
        options: ["100°",
            "101°",
            "105°",
            "190°"],
        correct_option: "100°"
    },
    {
        question: "11. When we keep materials in fridge it becomes cool due to,",
        options: ["Gain heat energy",
            "Lose cold energy",
            "Lose heat energy",
            "Gain cold energy"],
        correct_option: "Lose heat energy"
    },
    {
        question: "12. When ice melts , its temperature",
        options: ["Remains constant",
            "Increases",
            "Decreases",
            "Cannot say"],
        correct_option: "Remains constant"
    },
    {
        question: "13. 1 cal=",
        options: ["6.18 J",
            "4.18 J",
            "4.28 J",
            "5.18 J"],
        correct_option: "4.18 J"
    },

    {
        question: "14. The temperature of human body is 370C . Its temperature in Kelvin is",
        options: ["273 K",
            "300 K",
            "310 K",
            "350 K"],
        correct_option: "310 K"
    },
    {
        question: "15. Which metal does possess the specific heat of 0.092 cal/g-0 ?",
        options: ["Zinc",
            "Brass",
            "Copper",
            "Iron"],
        correct_option: "Brass"
    },
    {
        question: "16. Freezing of water takes place at___0C temperature.",
        options: ["0°",
            "100°C",
            "110°C",
            "-5°C"],
        correct_option: "0°"
    },

    {
        question: "17. Replace the'?' \n" +
            "Temperature in kelvin=?+Temperature in Celsius",
        options: ["700",
            "275",
            "546",
            "273"],
        correct_option: "273"
    },
    {
        question: "18. Absolute temperature is the temperature measured in a",
        options: ["Kelvin scale",
            "Celsius scale",
            "Fahrenheit scale",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Kelvin scale"
    },
    {
        question: "19. Temperature measured in kelvin scale is known as",
        options: ["Thermal equilibrium",
            "Constant temperature",
            "Absolute temperature",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Absolute temperature"
    },

    {
        question: "21. Convert 0° Celsius in kelvin",
        options: ["272",
            "270",
            "274",
            "273"],
        correct_option: "273"
    },
    {
        question: "22. The boiling point of water in kelvin is",
        options: ["373",
            "372",
            "371",
            "370"],
        correct_option: "373"
    },

    {
        question: "23. Iron of weight 2 kg was supplied with 12000 calories of heat. Initial temperature of iron was 20°C. Its specific heat is 0.1 cal/g-0C. What is the final temperature of iron ?",
        options: ["80°",
            "90°C",
            "100°C",
            "220°C"],
        correct_option: "80°"
    },
    {
        question: "24. If 200 cal. heat energy is required 40 grams of liquid to its gaseous state then the latent heat of vaporization is",
        options: ["4 cal/g",
            "5 cal/g",
            "8000 cal/g",
            "240 cal/g"],
        correct_option: "5 cal/g"
    },
    {
        question: "25. What does 'S' stands for in the equation Q= mS\Delta T ",
        options: ["Specific heat",
            "Specific temperature",
            "Difference in temperature",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Specific heat"
    },
]